# MARWA MONIER

#### CONTACT

Cairo, Cairo

**(**[])+20-1000052088

eng.marwa.05@gmail.com



www.linkedin.com/in/marwa-monier

#### **CORE QUALIFICATIONS**

Languages: Python, Keras, TensorFlow, C, C++, C#, Java, JEE (JSP/Servlet), SQL, ADO.NET, VB, VB.NET, Matlab,

Anaconda

- Applications: MS Visual Studio, Eclipse, Netbeans, Oracle
- Application Server: Tomcat
- Operating Systems: Windows, UNIX, Linux
- Database Systems: MS Access SQL Server, MySQL, Oracle (SQL-PL-SQL, Form Builder)
- Nanodegree Deep Learning Udacity
- Data Analysis Track Udacity
- Digital Marketing Challenger -Udacity
- Intro to Machine Learning Udacity
- Computer Maintenance & A+

#### **Personal Skills**

- Responsible ambitious and determined
- Ability to perform well under stress
- Ability to work individually or as an effective member of a team
- Organized and hard-working
- Ability to learn new tasks quickly according to the job needs and do them in a perfect way
- Communication & Language Skills
- Strong communication skills
- Ability to deal with all levels of management

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Machine Learning & Deep learning Certificated from Markov Academy
- Deep Learning Computer Vision

Resourceful Teaching Assistant and Researcher Assistant with more than 18 years of experience. Highly skilled in overseeing research office activities, recruiting talented support staff, and supervising students and staff. Talented in guiding all functions relating to research studies, analysis, and reporting.

Seeking a challenging position that offers me a consistently positive atmosphere to learn new technologies and implement them for the betterment of the business.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

January 2022 to Current

Research Assistant Zewailcity, Giza, Egypt

September 2020 to Current

Teaching Assistants Zewailcity, Giza, Egypt

September 2021 to February 2022

Computer Vision Teaching Assistant Cairo University Faculty of

Engineering, Giza, Egypt

January 2015 to Current

#### Software Developer Freelance

Developed new, efficient, and well-tested code for a variety of different software projects.

- Deep learning & machine learning.
- Developed and solved **Computer Vision** problems.
- Developed **Python** projects.
- Developed .Net projects.
- Developed C++ projects.

#### **Developed Database Projects:**

- Chemical system using Ado.net
- Hospital registration system using Ado.net
- Beauty center using ado.net
- InterContinental hotel database system using Ado.net and Oracle
- Design of (Flight-RES): a Flight Reservation Center using Ado.net and Oracle
- Grammar School Database System using Oracle database.
- Obaid Hospital Database System using Oracle database.
- Request Coursers Coordination System for university using Oracle database.
- Nursery database using Access.

<u>Java projects:</u> Designed and developed a web Application backend using JSP, Servlet, JDBC, SQL, and MySQL.

- Arabic verb Grammar (المحلل الصرفي للغة العربية)
- Health Smart Card
- Internet Application by java, servlet, and JSP
- Department Survey Tool
- Tea and coffee
- Water Pollutions Library System

#### AI Matlab Projects

- Arabic Text Recognition
- Flash Light Detection and Drawing

## CNN, OpenCV, YOLO, SSD & GANs - Udamy

- IBM-What is Data Science?-Coursera
- Deeplearning.ai Coursera
- Predicting House Prices with Regression using TensorFlow -Coursera
- Data Challenger Track-Egypt fwd -Udacity
- Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python) - Coursera
- HCIA-AI Huawei
- HCIA-Cloud Computing- Huawei
- 5G- Huawei
- ICDL Certificated

- Optical digit recognition using neural networks by Matlab
- Arabic Text Recognition using neural networks by Matlab and VB.net (Enhanced Version)

#### C++ Projects

- Educate English Alpha pits using Easy Windows
- Hang Man Game using Easy Windows
- Patients and doctor system
- Praying project VC++
- Ladder and Snake game

#### Others:

- Security Project
- RAS, Encryption and decryption Algorithms using vb.net
- File Encryption and Encrypted text embedded in an image and decryption (Steganography) using Matlab
- Operating system Projects
- CPU SCHEDULING SIMULATION by VB.Net and VC++
- · Deadlock detection Algorithms simulation using vb.net
- Traveling Salesman problem programming using lisp January 2005 to December 2008

#### Computer Instructor K.S.A, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

- Khadamate El Mogtamaa Facility, Riyadh Elm University
- Al Alamiah Institute For Computer & Technology
- Newhorizon As Instructor and Technical Support
- Alfaisal International Academy

#### **EDUCATION**

November 2020

#### Master of Science Faculty of Engineering

Cairo University, Cairo, Egypt

Thesis Title: Automatic Multi-Style Egyptian License Plate Detection and Classification in High-Resolution Videos Using Deep Learning Methods, GPA: 3.7

May 2004

### **B.Sc Engineering**

Cairo University, Cairo, Egypt

Graduation Project: Arabic Text Recognition (ATR) Grade: Excellent